PRATEEK GUPTA

SUMMARY

MICROSOFT CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL, SENIOR AGILE DEVELOPER & ARCHITECT ON MICROSOFT .NET AND WEB TECHNOLOGIES STACK

Expert in gathering, analyzing and defining business and functional requirements; evaluating possible solutions/tools; architecting solutions/enterprise integrations; code development and delivering successful implementations with view on ROI and time-to-market constraints. Ratio of hands on development to architecture is 80:20.

History of successful development, maintenance, and delivery of enterprise applications as part of consulting firms and investment banks over the last 15 years.

CONTACT INFO AND LINKS

Email jobhunt@prateekguru.com

Website http://prateekgupta.uk, http://prateekguru.com

Twitter @prateekgupta76 Phone 0778-929-5653

LinkedIn http://uk.linkedin.com/in/prateekguru Smarterer https://smarterer.com/prateekguru

SKILLS

Microsoft .NET, C#

WPF, Silverlight, XAML

ASP.NET, WCF, Web API Reactive Extensions, LINQ, Async Patterns

Html/CSS, JavaScript, Angular, NodeJS, etc.

Entity Framework, ORM Tools

MVC, MVVM, REST/SOAP, SOA

Agile, Scrum, TDD, BDD

Design Patterns, SOLID, IOC/DI

Jira, Git, Teamcity, SVN, Perforce, etc. Databases – Sybase, MS SQL Server

Microsoft Azure Cloud Dev & Infrastructure

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

SENIOR DEVELOPER / VICE PRESIDENT @ SOCIETE GENERALE (SGCIB), LONDON

September 2012 – Current

PROGRAMMER ANALYST @ MORGAN STANLEY, LONDON

August 2010 – September 2012

SENIOR MANAGER @ MORGAN STANLEY, INDIA

October 2005 - August 2010

DEPUTY CONSULTANT @ CSC, INDIA

2003 - 2005

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER @ HCL TECHNOLOGIES, INDIA

2000 - 2003

PROGRAMMER @ RSD SOFTWARE, INDIA

1999 - 2000

MAJOR PROJECTS

SG MARKETS EXECUTION PLATFORM, SOCIETE GENERALE

Architecture and development of new Web UI for the next generation of SG Markets Execution Platform using cutting edge web technologies for enterprise front-office application used by external and internal clients for trade execution on commodities and FX domain.

Technologies: Agile (Scrum), Html/JS (Angular, Jasmine, Bootstrap, Karma, Gulp, etc.), Asynchronous low latency messaging (Nirvana), ASP.Net Web API, Git, Jira, Teamcity

ALPHA SINGLE DEALER PLATFORM (SDP), SOCIETE GENERALE

Development of core common components and framework for the application. Development of FX RFS and ESP trading capabilities with low latency asynchronous messaging over Nirvana middleware. Refactoring and isolation of core framework classes to improve continuous deployment and integration.

Technologies: Agile (Scrum), Silverlight with Blend, MVVM/Prism, IOC/DI using Autofac, Windows Services (C#), Nirvana messaging, SVN, Jira, Teamcity

MATRIX, MORGAN STANLEY

Responsible for integration of Morgan Stanley Research feed from the KMS platform into Matrix portal. Developed middle-tier framework for the same. Created an Outlook based solution to allow internal users to publish commentaries and articles using E-mail. These articles were pushed to Matrix portal.

Technologies: Agile (Scrum), WPF, VBA, Exchange, Windows Services (C#), WCF/REST, Perforce, Jira

CONNECT, MORGAN STANLEY

Connect provides content amalgamation and distribution to Equities Sales and Trading Business. Responsible for requirements analysis, development, testing, delivery and support for the entire life-cycle of the project.

Technologies: Microsoft .NET, C#, Silverlight, MVVM, Prism, Unity, Blend, Perforce

KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (KEY), MORGAN STANLEY

KMS (Knowledge Management System) provided content management, collaboration, search and distribution of internally generated content and historic documents to various business units in the firm. Provided SOA based middle tier API to MSSB Business Unit and supported more than 30K users. Performed various roles, such as architect, developer, analyst, support, infrastructure lead, scrum master during the seven year involvement in project.

Technologies: Agile (Scrum), Microsoft .NET, C#, ASP.NET, AJAX, WCF, Sybase, Memcache, NHibernate, JavaScript/JQuery

Page | 2 Prateek GUPTA

EDUCATION

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN ADVANCED COMPUTING, CDAC-ACTS, INDIA

JULY 1999 - JANUARY 2000

6 months post graduate certification and diploma in software engineering from CDAC (Center for Development of Advanced Computing, India). Passed in Grade A.

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING, DAYALBAGH EDUCATION INSTITUTE, INDIA JULY 1994 – MAY 1998

1st Division in Mechanical Engineering from Faculty of Engineering, Dayalbagh Educational Institute, Agra.

INDIAN SCHOOL CERTIFICATE / (SIXTH FORM EQUIVALENT), INDIA 1992 - 1994

1st Division with Distinction in Science & Maths stream.

INDIAN COUNCIL FOR SECONDARY EDUCATION / (GCSE EQUIVALENT), INDIA 1992

1st Division with Distinction.

DISCLOSURES

RIGHT TO WORK

Tier 1 (General) Visa holder. Expires May 2016.

Would be eligible for Indefinite Leave to Remain (ILR) before expiry.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE ON REQUEST

Page | 3 Prateek GUPTA